PRAGNESH PATEL

Sr. IT Technology Leader
OGSM | Agile | Omni Channel

CONTACT

(510) 221-8146

ppatel5600@gmail.com

• Fremont, CA

in linkedin.com/in/pragnesh2

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Electronics Eng,

University of Pune, Maharashtra, India

PROFILE

Senior IT Technology Leader with over 20 years of retail technology experience in creating and managing highly impactful technical teams in omnichannel experience, setting up the vision, and implementing strategic roadmaps in retail organizations with revenue of \$1B-\$20B.

CAREER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Sales Growth

Played a key role in uplifting digital sales growth for Kohl's from \$3B to \$5B in 2 years by delivering Omni Channel capabilities focusing on customer experience and engagement.

Launching New Brands

I was very instrumental in supporting business stakeholders with the Launch of new brands like Crazy 8 and Janie & Jack within Gymboree by leveraging existing IT infrastructure and resources.

Cost Optimization

At Kohl's, I reduced IT spend for my team from \$12M to \$7M over the course of 2 years by bringing in a greater emphasis on automation and rationalizing team structure.

Building High performance teams

Responsible for creating a team of 100+ Engineers from the ground-up which brought in greater Agility and reduced time to market.

Transformation projects

Created Strategy and vision to implement CICD pipeline, and introduced AI Bot that helped in removing manual steps that delivered speed and quality with frequent deployments to production.

Building Engineering Foundation

- Communicating goals and roles with clarity
- Removing Silos and promoting collaboration
- Motivated team members promoting productivity and quality

SKILLS

Critical Thinking | Collaboration | Team Management | Strong Work Ethic Adaptability | Time Management | Handling Pressure

TECHNOLOGY

Omni-channel Commerce - ATG, Hybris, micro services-oriented architecture

Cloud - GCP, Amazon AWS and Microsoft Azure

Mobile - Native apps, Mobile Web

BigData - Google Big query, Apache Hive, Hadoop

Database - Oracle, Mongo db, My SQL

BI – Tableau, Microstrategy

Info Security and Compliance – ADA, PCI, CCPA, SOX

Automation tools and Framework – Selenium, cucumber, J behave, TestNG, Robot, Saucelabs, HeadSpin

Performance – Jmeter, Loadrunner

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kohl's Corp - Milpitas, CA - MANAGER, ENGINEERING

SEPT 2015 - PRESENT

Kohl's is a American department store retail chain, operated by Kohl's Corporation. It is the largest department store chain in the United States, with 1,158 locations, operating stores in every U.S. state except Hawaii.

- Leading and managing a team of 100+ engineers directly responsible for all Kohl's digital channels with revenue over \$5 Billion.
- Responsible for managing a budget of over \$10M
- Program management of multiple projects with resource allocation, scope management, and budget management.
- Responsible for Kohl's platform automation for web store, mobile channels and Big Data/Analytics platforms.
- Implemented/integrated with industry-leading tools for automated testing including real device testing for Mobile and Web.

PRAGNESH PATEL

Sr. IT Technology Leader OGSM | Agile|Omni Channel

CONTACT

(510) 221-8146

ppatel5600@gmail.com

• Fremont, CA

in linkedin.com/in/pragnesh2

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Electronics Eng,

University of Pune, Maharashtra, India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Responsible for managing a team of test engineers for Big Data/Analytics platform on google Big query validating data ingestion, transformation, and aggregation through various source systems and data quality for Tableau reporting.
- Mentored team to work more cross-functionally to achieve great results and high impact.
- Collaborated with product management and development teams for delivering high-quality customer-facing functionalities.
- Managing global teams of 100+ engineers working on Automation.
- Responsible for maintaining the road map, recruiting talent, and
 management of the budget. Managed test automation teams during
 migration from Legacy to cloud platform in record time with highest quality
 standards with no major issues and seamless roll out to our customers
 which resulted in high conversion and record sales across digital channels
 during the peak holiday season.
- Responsible for providing quality metrics and KPIs to senior executives.
- Reformed Quality testing teams from manual to Automation and reduced time to market significantly with quick turn around time and continuous feedback loop to development teams.
- Played a key role in establishing the CICD pipeline, creating selenium grid infrastructure in the cloud, and leveraging third-party tools for browser testing.
- Implemented BOT for faster analysis of automation failures using failure patterns.

GYMBOREE CORP - SAN FRANCISCO, CA

MAR 2002 - AUG 2015

Specialty children clothing company with multiple brands like Gymboree, Janie and Jack, and Play and Music with retail locations.

SR. MANAGER, Ecommerce and Store Systems

MAR 2011 - AUG 2015

- As Sr. Manager for Ecommerce, I was responsible for E-commerce and store systems development and testing including POS.
- I was responsible for creating and Maintaining a road map for the organization working with key stakeholders.
- My responsibility included working directly with Business stakeholders and providing them with technical solutions to business needs.
- Managed team of 40 + people in the Engineering discipline across
- development, Quality Engineering, and performance.
- Implemented Automation test suite for POS and Ecommerce
- functionality using QTP and Selenium.

MANAGER, Ecommerce and Store Systems

MAR 2008 - FEB 2011

- Responsible for a team of 25 people including development, quality engineers, and performance engineers.
- Responsible for overseeing the development and testing for all Ecommerce projects for Gymboree.com, janieandjack.com, shadeclothing.com, and crazy8.com also responsible for QA projects for retail point of sale applications used in 1000+ stores in the US.
- Responsible for making sure that all projects follow strict testing guidelines for PCI and SOX.
- Participate in design review meetings, defect review meetings for various projects and ensure high-quality deliverables.
- Worked with the Development lead/manager to ensure the
- effectiveness and quality of the components and systems developed
 Worked closely with other team members in the company analyzing and testing external system APIs for integration testing.

LEAD Ecommerce and Store Systems

MAR 2002 - FEB 2008

- Responsible for leading a team of 5 Engineers.
- Develop test methodology and test strategy based on the project requirement.
- Preparation of various documents in compliance with approved SDLC methodologies of the department.
- Coordinating with the development team and testing teams.

Work Authorization: No work permit is required.